We chase the birds, stare at the stars and measure the sky,
我們追逐飛鳥 仰望繁星 思忖蒼穹
just want to divine our ephemeral future.
只為知曉我們短渺的一生
Now you guide wings, stay close to the etoiles and move the heaven.
如今 你為鳳鸞所導引 投奔北斗 震爍星空
You shall be a precious spirit.
你將化身尊貴的精靈
As a part of world from this sandy land,
你的靈魂將在這無盡的沙地
light your soul forever.
成為世界的源泉永世光明
From the mud castle ship, we keep our minds on you.
而我們將在這泥之城船上 永遠思念著你
Guide us, please.
願你指引我們的前路
July 2, 93 S.S.
砂刑曆93年7月2日
Benihi (Shirushi)'s funeral has been held.
舉行了貝妮希（印）的葬禮
She was 29,
享年29歲
served as a teaching staff.
生前是教育工作者
We flow the dead into the sea of sand.
我們會讓逝者沉入沙之海
Whoever sends the dead at this time must not let the tears sink.
在這時候 為逝者送行的人是不能流淚的
Because you will be called by the souls sleeping under of the sand, they will beckon you in.
否則會被沙海深處的無盡魂靈所召喚 早早墜身沙中
That is the tale handed down.
有著 這樣的傳說
Ah, you can't cry here Chakuro.
啊 查克羅 說了不可以哭的
Don't cry,
不可以哭的
or you will be called by the dead.
會被逝者帶走的
C'mon, clench your fingers.
快 十指扣緊
Restrain yourself, Chakuro.
忍住 要忍住哦查克羅
Restrain, restrain.
忍住忍住
You idoit...
笨蛋…
Ah, I goofed again.
啊 又搞砸了
My name is Chakuro.
我叫查克羅
I am 14 years old, male.
14歲 男性
The recording clerk of the mud whale.
負責「泥鯨」的記錄工作
Many times each time I see off a friendly person,
伴隨著一次次與摯友的別離
my urge to record is increasing.
我就更加懷揣著 想要記錄一切的衝動
According to my grandfather, who was a Muin,
按「無印」的祖父的說法
I am sickening from an illness
hypergraphia
hypergraphia
而我正是得了這種病
The drifting boat on the endless sea of sand.
在這無邊沙海裡漂流的我們的流浪船——
The population of our mud whale was 513.
「泥鯨」的人口為513人
Our lives were together with the sand, the wind and the sunlight.
我們的生活 與風沙日曬同在
Concentrate!
集中注意力
You should get it down slow~ly!
輕輕～地降下來哦
Get it down slow~ly!
輕輕～地降下來
Oh yeah, everyone's handy!
對的對的 大家都好能幹
You guys have made a lot of progresses.
長進不少嘛 小傢伙們
Chakuro!
查克羅
Cuz they have a good teacher!
果然是因為老師好嘛
Yeah.
是呢
Everyone is better than Chakuro already!
小朋友們已經比查克羅還要能幹了
Don't tease me!
好過分啊
Listen, a Shirushi shouldn't work as a recording clerk.
本來 印是不會去做記錄工作的啊
sentikinesis
thymia
You are wasting your thymia!
難得的「情念力」派不上用場了不是
You were appointed as a recording clerk,
你會被任命去做記錄工作
just cuz you're not good at thymia, right?
不就是因為你實在不擅長「情念力」嘛
They are even calling me the destroyer!
destroyer
Don't tease yourself!
自己都承認了嗎
By the way,
說起來
we were also learning thymia
我跟莎米也是像這樣
from Benihi in this way, right?
讓貝妮希教我們學會「情念力」的呢
Chakuro,
查克羅
forget about Benihi.
忘了貝妮希吧
We can't leave ourselves trapped in the death of others,
要是為了一次次的生離死別傷心
or we Shirushi are not able to live through.
我們印是沒辦法安心活下去的
Yep.
是的呢
sentikinesis
thymia
Shirushi is the name of those who can handle thymia from emotions.
所謂「印」是指能通過感情發動「情念力」的能力者
Nine in ten of the inhabitants of the mud whale are Shirushi.
在泥鯨上 有9成的人都屬於這種
We Shirushi are all like Benihi whom we sent off yesterday.
印就像昨天送別的貝妮希那樣
We are all short-lived.
大家壽命都很短
Chakuro!
查克羅
Cut some leaves of omasa bamboos from your place!
從那裡切點大真沙竹的葉子來
Since they will be used for food preservation,
要用來包食品的
pick 5 to 6 new leaves from as tall as possible.
儘量選樹梢上的嫩葉子 來5 6枚
Please use that!
用這個
5 to 6 leaves, 5 to 6 leaves...
5 6枚 5 6枚
Chakuro!
查克羅！
Who said you'd chop the tree!
誰讓你砍樹了！
Stop! Don't run away Chakuro!
喂 站住 查克羅！
Get back!
給我回來！
What the fuss?
鬧什麼呢
Dunno.
誰知道
Hide me!
讓我躲進來
What have you done?
你又幹什麼了
Oh nothing serious.
啊沒 沒什麼大不了的
Close the window, sand's entering.
會進沙的 快關上
Sorry sorry.
抱歉抱歉
What's that?
這是什麼？
We're making your goggles.
在給你們做護目鏡
For protection from the sand?
防沙用的？
You've picked up acrylic boards for us the other day, right?
之前你不是給我們撿來壓克力板了嗎
Thatz for you, though it's just a prototype.
這個送你 雖然是試製品
Cool!
好酷！
The thick body is simply too great for me!
這個厚重感讚到不得了
Decoration is a hobby of this workshop, but it's not that useful.
裝飾是我們工作室的興趣 沒什麼實用性的
As a return, if you find something from the sea or the islands,
作為交換 要是海上啊島上啊撿到什麼好東西了
bring them right here without declaration!
不要申報 直接拿咱們這來
I'll show it off to Sami later.
待會也跟莎米炫耀炫耀
Hello, chief.
首長好
You are wearing cool stuffs!
裝備得這麼酷
Are you going out to the sea?
要出海嗎？
No, I am on my way to Suo.
不 我正要去蘇澳那裡
With your records, right?
是帶記錄去的吧
Is that for the funeral of Benihi?
這是貝妮希葬禮的部分？
Isn't it over writing too much?
寫太多了吧
The paper is precious, use it moderately.
要適可而止一點 紙可是很貴重的
I appreciate it.
沒什麼不好的吧
Chakuro's record is useful.
查克羅的記錄很有用的
It looks like a diary rather than an official record.
與其說是正式記錄 不如說像日記一樣
I just can't stop writing.
寫起來就停不下來了
Maybe I'm not suit for recording clerk,
我也覺得自己不適合從事記錄工作
but I wonder if the people who lived in our mud whale
但是 我總在想
could have written more about those happened in the past.
要是以前住在泥鯨上的人能多留下一點當時的記錄就好了
Then why we came to live on this island?
比如為什麼會住到這個島上來
And why our mud whale does never sink?
比如為什麼泥鯨不會沉沒
We may understand these
要是當年留下了更多的記錄
if there are more records left.
我們或許就能夠理解這些
So I write for the future.
所以我為未來而揮毫
Do your best!
加油
Yes!
好的
Those who do not have the power of thymia,
首長和長老會的人沒有「情念力」
are called Muin.
被稱作「無印」
Most of the Shirushi die in their twenties.
和通常二三十歲就撒手人寰的「印」不同
In the contrast, Muin are long-living.
無印的人很長壽
They live as the leaders of the mud whale.
他們作為泥鯨的領導者活下去
Come in.
請進
Hello, Suo.
你好 蘇澳
Hi Chakuro.
喲 查克羅
I am bringing you the records.
我把記錄帶來了
Thank you.
謝謝
Did you cry the whole night last night?
昨天哭了一晚上嗎？
No... I mean...
啊不… 那個
I was crying too.
我也哭了
Keep it our secret.
不要跟別人說哦
Benihi was a nice person.
貝妮希是個好人
There is no emotion recorded in your writings.
你的文筆並沒有代入絲毫感情
But they are very sentimental.
但卻是如此的令人傷感
Because it's a rule not to write any emotions down.
因為規定了文字裡不能帶有感情
Chakuro,
查克羅
I'm sorry you have to record so many painful things.
總是讓你做這樣痛苦的記錄 抱歉了
There's nothing I can help you...
而我卻什麼也做不到…
Why are you apologizing?
為 為什麼要道歉啊
Suo is doing researches on extending the lives of Shirushi.
蘇澳做著延長印的壽命的研究
And you sincerely feel sorrow for our short lives, more than anyone else.
比誰都要更為印的短命而憤慨
You truly have shed more tears than me!
流的淚要比我這樣的人多得多
I am stupid, writing a lot of records is the only thing I can do.
像我這樣的笨蛋只能草草記下大量的記錄
But you are clever and will have a long live!
而你既聰明又長壽
Please solve this world's mystery
請務必解開世界的謎團
and make people on this ship much much happier!
讓船上的人們過上更加幸福的生活
Thank you, Chakuro.
謝謝你 查克羅
Here, when people can not hold their emotions on their bodies,
這裡的人們在感情難以自抑的時候
they clench their fingers in this manner
會像這樣十指緊扣
to get their feelings under control.
壓抑自己的情感
These records will be with you even after I die.
就算我死了 這份記錄也會與你同在
I hope they can help you in the future.
希望它能為未來奉獻上一絲微薄的力量
It's an adrift island!
是漂流島！
It's the first adrift island in the past 6 months.
距上次發現漂流島已經有半年了
We have 5 days to go to the island for procurement.
大概只有這五天左右能上島吧
After that, it would become difficult since it will be too far.
五天後距離遠了就困難了
Let's send a reconnaissance team first tomorrow.
明天首先派偵察隊過去
Then we will procure goods if it's safe.
那麼 如果安全的話之後進行物資的搜集
Please scout for a reconnaissance team until tomorrow, Suo.
偵察隊的人選明天之前由蘇澳決定
Do me a favor.
交給你了
Got it.
知道了
The next morning we left when the sea was calm.
第二天早上 趁著風平浪靜我們出發了
Why is Chakuro here?
為什麼查克羅也來了啊
Hope we are not go into troubles this time.
別鬧出什麼事故就好
It's amazing that Suo chose Sami.
真虧得蘇澳會選莎米呢
We all know it could be dangerous.
明明說不定會有什麼危險
My brother trusts me.
因為哥哥信賴我啊
Go!
衝啊！
After enter the sea,
出海之後
you will sink in the sand if you do not use the thymia.
要是不使用「情念力」就會為沙海所吞沒
Using thymia to float the leave boat
讓竹葉扁舟漂浮前進所使用的「情念力」
consumes as much stamina as running at full speed.
就像全力奔跑一樣消耗大量體力
Therefore the distance we can arrive is limited.
所以能夠探索的距離有限
Listen, never act individually.
聽好了 不許單獨行動
Also, do not pick anything up since it's recce this time.
還有 這次是偵察 什麼都別拿
Yes sir.
好
Sami.
莎米
Thank you.
謝謝
You are hot on each other!
打得火熱呢
Impossible!
才怪！
Hey Sami, don't go alone!
啊莎米 說了不許單獨行動的
I'm fine!
別管我
But here is different from the islands I've seen.
話說回來 這裡和過往漂流而過的島嶼有所不同
It's something that people used.
是人用的東西
I guess it's a weapon.
看起來是武器
There were islands where we can find something people left.
迄今為止也有在其他島上發現過昔人用過的東西
But we have never found any people.
但從來沒有見到過人
The guys in the workshop will be happy right?
工作室的傢伙們要高興了呢
Sami?
是吧 莎米
What?
咦
What should I do?
怎麼辦
Hey, Sami!
喂 莎米
What are you?
什麼啊…
Wait!
等等
Hey, I said wait!
喂 讓你等下
What's this?
這是什麼
Food?
食品？
Hi.
那個…
Are you OK?
沒事吧
Tears...
淚水…
What's wrong?
你怎麼了
Are you injured?
受傷了嗎
She was the first human I met outside of our mud whale.
她 是除了泥鯨住民以外我遇見的第一個「人」
If we could call her a human
如果她那時的狀態
considering her status at that time.
可以算作「人」的話
But...
但是…
Stop it!
住手！
She is weakening.
這姑娘 力量在消退
As I expected...
果然
She is injured.
受傷了
She has washed her clothes.
洗過衣服嗎
Hey, you'd go together?
喂 連你也要跟來嗎
Maybe it's her pet.
是她的伙伴嗎
Hey, where's Chakuro?
咦 查克羅去哪了
I lost him on the way...
途中走散了…
Masoo.
瑪索
Hey Chakuro!
喂 查克羅！
I told you not to act individually!
不是說了不許單獨行動的
And I said don't pick anything...
還撿來這麼大個東西…
She is not anything!
那個 這不是東西
She is a person!
是人 人
Oh my god...
開什麼玩笑
What should we do, captain?
怎麼辦 隊長
She is weakening, she may die if we leave her alone!
她很衰弱 放著不管搞不好會死的
We interrupted the reconnaissance of the island,
我們急忙結束了對島的偵察
and decided to take the girl to the mud whale.
決定把那個少女帶回泥鯨
How beautiful she is.
好漂亮…
Sami, could you put these clothes on her?
莎米 能幫她穿上這身衣服嗎
I think they are hers.
我想是她的
Yup.
嗯
lykos
lykos
This scar... It seems that she get injured for quite some days.
這個傷痕 應該傷了很久了
Should I tell others about I was attacted by her with her thymia?
她用「情念力」襲擊我的事情
Better not I think.
還是不說比較好吧
It's raining.
啊 下雨了
Wow... It's a sunshower!
哇 明明是晴天
It feels good!
好舒服
Rainwater will be stored in the reservoir of mud whale,
雨水會被儲存到泥鯨的貯水池內
very important for our lives.
是攸關我們生活的重要資源
Also, it was said that rain is auspicious.
而且 雨天也曾被認為是吉兆
It's a rainbow!
彩虹
Surely something good is going to happen!
一定會有好事呢
Yeah!
嗯
In our closed little world,
或許這位少女
may this girl
給我們封閉的小小世界
brings the future unknown to everyone.
帶來了無人能知的未來
Everybody in our recce team is excited.
偵察隊員們都情緒高漲
For me, the first one who found her, in particular...
特別是第一個發現她的我…
Ah, I can't record any emotion.
啊 不能帶上感情寫
What happened? Aren't you too fast?
怎麼回事 太快了吧
Emergency!
緊急事態喔
We picked up something terribly good!
撿了個不得了的東西
What!
什麼
You are supposed not to take anything back today!
不是規定好了今天什麼都不能帶回來的嗎
I will denounce you to the presbytery!
我要向長老會告狀
Shut up, your puss-head!
閉嘴你這大頭鬼
What are you saying, you muscle idiot!
什麼你這肌肉大傻瓜
Stop, you two!
快停下來你們倆
C'mon and clench your fingers!
快 十指扣緊
You don't wanna be internal moles, right?
你們想做「體內鼴鼠」嗎
Go see it with your own eyes!
你這傢伙 用你的狗眼看清楚了
There's a person on that island!
那個島上有人
A person?
人？
This girl.
這個姑娘
A per... person!?
人 人！？
Tai.. Taisha-sama!
台 台霞姐姐！
Ah, she is awakened.
啊 醒過來了
αὔρα
αὔρα
An aura!
念紋！
Will she attack us?
要幹架嗎
You can't do it!
這樣不行啊
Here in the mud whale,
用「情念力」打鬧
you can't fight with thymia or you will be punished!
在泥鯨上是會受罰的
Release me.
放開我
She spoke...
開口了
The same language...
語言是一樣的
Seems I've been captured.
我當了…俘虜呢
I won't resist.
我不會抵抗
I'm the only one left.
只剩我一個人了
I surrender.
我要…投降
This way, watch your step please.
這邊 請留心腳下
Thank you.
謝謝
Aye, it's my pleasure!
啊不 這是我應該的
Where is the girl from that island?
島上的姑娘怎麼了？
She... Chakuro and Sami have taken her to the medical office.
這個… 查克羅和莎米帶她去醫務室了
Oh dear.
哎呀
That two brats!
這兩個臭小子！
What's your name?
你叫什麼名字？
No.
沒有的
You have one!
有的呀
Λύκος
λύκος
Lykos, embroidered on your clothes!
你衣服上繡著「黎可斯」
Lykos, huh...
黎可斯啊
Lykos, don't you shock in such an completely unknown place?
黎可斯到了完全陌生的地方不會害怕嗎
If I were you, my heart's throbbing.
要是我的話心臟都嚇得怦怦跳了
I'm curious if I were her!
我的話可是會興趣盎然呢
No.
沒有的
Here is the medical office?
這裡是醫務室？
Only young people here...
都是年輕人
They are Shirushi.
這些是印的人
Their abilities of thymia and stamina decreased after the age of 30 or so.
到30歲左右「情念力」的能力和體力都會下降
Some people even became bedridden.
還有會臥床不起的人
Is it the same in your world?
你的世界也是這樣的嗎
No.
沒有的
Φάλαινα
φάλαινα
Is here Fallaina?
這裡 是「法萊那」嗎
Fallaina?
法萊那？
It's mud whale here.
這裡是泥鯨喔
Everyone calls here like that.
大家都這麼叫
Chakuro, Sami.
查克羅 莎米
Chief.
首長
You have protected this girl, right?
是你們保護了這個姑娘嗎
Good job.
辛苦了
Hello.
你好
I'm the chief here, my name is Taisha.
我是首長台霞
I wonder if you can follow me.
能請你跟我走嗎
Wait a minute please, chief.
等等首長
Where are you going?
你們要去哪裡？
I will introduce her to the presbyters.
去向長老會介紹她
But she is injured and needs medical treatment.
這之前得給她療傷…
You are kind.
你們倆真體貼
But don't worry, we will take care of her.
不過沒關係的 我們會照顧好她的
Suo, deal with the internal moles please.
蘇澳 「體內鼴鼠」那邊就拜託了
Yes.
好的
Lykos...
黎可斯…
Brother!
哥哥！
Have you seen? She's the girl on that island!
看到了嗎 那就是島上的姑娘
I wonder if I can be her friend!
莎米 能跟她交上朋友嗎
It would be nice to be so.
是呢 希望你們能成為朋友
Yup!
嗯
Suo, what's wrong with the internal moles?
蘇澳 「體內鼴鼠」做了什麼嗎
Since there is a rainbow, they are pardoned.
因為出彩虹了 決定赦免他們
Oni's guys?
歐尼他們？
I'm going to release them.
我現在去釋放他們
But I'm just wondering what will they do
可是要是讓他們知道了漂流島上發現了人…
if they know a person has been found on an adrift island.
不知道他們會做出什麼事來
I'll go with you
我也一起去
as a bodyguard.
做保鏢
Let's go together!
莎米也要去
No way, Sami should return to work.
不行 莎米回去做事
Nah!
哎～
I wonder whether it was caught on that island too?
難道說這也是從島上捉來的？
Eh, it follow me itself.
呃 啊 它是自己跟來的
Seems delicious.
看起來很好吃呢
Oh, yeah...
啊 是呢
In the mud whale, those who breaks the rule
在泥鯨上 破壞規則的人
would be jailed in an area called the internal.
將被關押在地下被稱為「體內」的區域
For some reason, thymia can not be used there.
不知為何 在那裡無法發動「情念力」
For us short-living Shirushi,
對於壽命短暫的印們來說
it was really sad to lose our freedom and be sent into the internal.
被剝奪自由 關在體內是很痛苦的處分
But there were guys who repeat violating the rule
可是 卻有一群屢屢違反規則
and get jailed times and times.
一次又一次被收監的人
Since they have spent so long in the internal,
因為他們長年累月在體內生活
they were called the internal moles.
被稱為「體內鼴鼠」
It is an amnesty.
你們獲得恩赦了
Get out.
快出來
Ah, my body is hurt!
啊 身體好痛
It's dazzling!
好耀眼
We are so honored that the next chief is welcoming us in person.
居然是下任首長親自來迎接我們
Do not repeat absurd things.
不要再做蠢事
Treasure your limited time.
珍惜你們有限的時光
Treasure?
珍惜？
They are the same for us.
對我們來說都沒差
It doesn't matter we are underground or on the ship.
地下也罷船上也罷
In such a small world, nothing is different for us.
這麼微小的世界不管做什麼都沒什麼兩樣
You Muin have a long life.
你們這些無印來日方長
You have enough time to treasure stuffs such as a mud ship.
或許還會把這泥船當個寶吧
There is something I have to tell you now.
先告訴你們
Today, we found a person on a adrift island.
今天 在漂流島上發現了人
What? Really?
喂 真的嗎
A person? Outside?
有人？在「外面」？
Do not overreact.
不要反應過度
Since you are still...
你們本來就是…
After all there are worlds outside.
果然天外有天啊
There are worlds where people live.
還有其他有人的世界
We can't tell it yet...
這還沒有…
We are going out.
我們要出去
As long as there is another world outside,
既然外面還有別的世界
I will leave this trivial ship behind.
這麼狹小的破船就扔掉它
Oni!
歐尼
Where was that person?
那個人在哪裡
I can not tell you.
我不能說
Don't depend on him.
別指望那傢伙
Wait us, Oni!
等等啊 歐尼
Oni!
歐尼
Oni is the leader of the internal moles.
歐尼是體內鼴鼠的領袖
It was said that he is the top psychic of thymia in the mud whale.
「情念力」的能力在泥鯨上也被譽為獨一無二
Indeed...
簡直是…
Right what I was worried...
跟我擔心的一絲不差
They may do something to Lykos!
他們搞不好會對黎可斯做什麼
I am going there!
我去看看
Chakuro!
查克羅
Lykos...
黎可斯
There is only Lykos, and the presbyters.
只有長老他們和黎可斯在嗎
Tell me the name of your country.
告訴我你來自哪個國家
Have you been dispatched from the home country?
你是「本國」派遣來的嗎
Home country?
「本國」？
What are they talking about?
那是什麼
Please answer my question first.
請先回答我的問題
Φάλαινα
φάλαινα
Is here Fallaina?
這裡 是「法萊那」嗎
I can not answer you.
無法回答
Unless we fully understand your purpose,
只有我們清楚知道了你的目的
we can not reveal our identity.
才能告訴你我們的身份
What do they mean?
怎麼回事？
Seems presbyters understand what Lykos is saying.
長老他們知道黎可斯在說什麼嗎
I was forced to be brought here.
被帶到這裡並非我本意
What about your fellows on the island?
島上的同伴呢
They all died.
全都死了
I buried them.
是我埋葬了他們
Didn't you feel anything?
你不覺得痛苦嗎
Such as painful...
那份感情
No.
沒有的
απάθεια
απάθεια
She is an apatheia...
是傀儡嗎…
People without emotion...
沒有感情的人
Oh my goodness...
這是何等殘酷
Απάθεια
απάθεια
Apatheia? What's that?
傀儡？ 那是什麼
The world is still what it was in the past.
果然 世界還是一點都沒有改變
It seems that there is no point in talking with you any more.
繼續問你也沒什麼意義了
Excuse me, but I have to restrain you.
不好意思 我們得把你關起來
Lykos...
黎可斯
What are you saying?
你怎麼了？
It told you to be careful upon your head!
它讓你留心頭頂上呢
Oni!
歐尼
Stop it!
住手
Don't you know what will happen if you do this?
你知道這樣會有什麼下場嗎
I am going to see her world.
我要去看看這傢伙的世界
You guys just play with your treasurable mud ship all your lives!
你們就在這泥船裡玩一輩子扮家家酒吧
Lykos...
黎可斯…
Help, help...
來人 來人啊…
What's up?
怎麼了？
It must not...
不行啊…
If you make contact with the world,
要是接觸了世界
the woes will overtake you.
會釀成災難的
Oni escaped with that island girl!
歐尼拐走島上的少女逃跑了
Pursue him as soon as possible!
快派人追上去
Oni,
歐尼
what are you planning to do?
你要做什麼
I'm going to her island.
我要去這傢伙的島上
You participated in the recce team right?
你參加了偵察隊的吧
Yep.
嗯
Guide me.
給我帶路
There are plenty of things I want to write about the mud whale.
關於泥鯨 我想要書寫的事情數不勝數
Stacked sun-dried bricks, painted with mud, we had a toy-like castle city.
堆疊起曬乾的土坯 用泥塗抹強化的宛如玩具般的塔狀的城裡
Lots of people were living there together.
許許多多的人們相濡以沫 共同生活至今
I am sure you will be surprised as you are living in an extensive world.
生活在廣袤世界的你們一定會感到驚奇吧
But it was the entirety of our precious world.
這座小島 就是我們所珍重的世界的一切
No matter what occurs,
我曾經決心不管遇到什麼
I am going to write everything happens to us.
我都要書寫下
The first section
第 一 節
It was the Entirety of Our Precious World
第 一 節
I was determined to keep on writing.
我 們 所 珍 重 的
乾いた海の跡　望んで
乾いた海の跡　望んで
Staring into the trace of the dried sea
眺望昔日的大海
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
I will draw the other side I have never seen
描繪未知的彼岸
囚われの心のままなら
囚われの心のままなら
If you remain your heart in captivity
如果囚禁起心靈  一如過往
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
You may live without knowing the pain
又怎麼會經歷如此悲傷
美しい詞を告げたひと
美しい詞を告げたひと
The one who told the beautiful story
是誰講述起美好的希望
夜明けも待たずに
夜明けも待たずに
Can not wait for the dawn
讓我等不及黎明
果てのその先を泳ぐ
果てのその先を泳ぐ
Until beyond the end of world, I am swimming
向著天涯海角揚帆起航
虫の唄
虫の唄
Listen to the insects' song
徹夜蟲鳴
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
That night is our memory
回憶裡與你一起側耳傾聽
手を　ただ結んで
手を　ただ結んで
Just link hand in hand
只是雙手相牽
半色でも　遠い国でも
半色でも　遠い国でも
No matter it is twilight or a distant country
不論夕陽  還是遠方
短い一章に生まれた夢を
短い一章に生まれた夢を
Born in a short chapter
在這短暫蒼渺的一章裡
抱きしめに行こう
抱きしめに行こう
But let us go and embrace that dream
一起追逐夢想
The second section
第 二 節
Fallaina
φάλαινα
The Sinners of the Whale
鯨 的 罪 人 們